sotc.in 2016-05-05

# Privacy Policy - Kuoni together with SOTC

**Kuoni Travel (India) Private Limited (KUONI)** believes that customer who books or looks for any services at www.sotc.in (Site) has the right to know about the privacy policy that is followed by us. For the trust the client has on KUONI, we value the right to your privacy.

The idea of this policy is to educate the user as to what personal information is being captured by us and where the same is being used. It describes the principles and practices that apply to Personal Information (defined below) collected from users of our services (“you”) on our Site, in telephone or e-mail communications, or in interviews, surveys, sweepstakes, contests, or raffles.

## In short

  * We will not collect Personal Information without your knowledge and permission
  * We will not knowingly disclose your Personal Information to third parties, except as provided in this Privacy Policy
  * We will take reasonable steps to protect the security of the Personal Information we collect from you. 

## For unregistered users

We encourage you to register with us in order to book services on our website and to take advantage of our customization features. However, you may choose not to register and take advantage of any feature of our site where registration is not required.

If you do not register, then the information we collect from you is limited.

We log your IP address in order to help diagnose problems with our server, administer our Web site and track usage statistics.

Your IP address may vary each time you visit, or it may be the same, depending on whether you access our site through an always-on type of Internet connection (e.g., cable modem or DSL), or through a dial-up connection (e.g., VSNL, MTNL etc). Either way, it would be extremely difficult for us to identify you through your IP address, and we make no attempt to do so.

If you reached our site by clicking on a link or advertisement on another site, then we also log that information. This helps us to maximize our Internet exposure, and to understand the interests of our users. All of this information is collected and used only in the aggregate; that is, it is entered into our database, where we can use it to generate overall reports on our visitors, but not reports about individual visitors.

We also place a small file known as a “cookie” on your computer’s hard drive. A cookie may contain information that allows us to track your path through our Web site and to determine whether you have visited us before. However, unless you register with us, it contains no personally identifiable information that would allow us to identify you. Cookies cannot be used to read data off of your hard drive, and cannot retrieve information from any other cookies created by other Web sites. We use cookies in this manner to help us understand how visitors use our site, and to help us to improve our site. You may refuse to accept a cookie from us by following the procedures specific to your Web browser. Although you may do so, you may find that your browser reacts strangely when visiting not only our Web site, but other Web sites as well. Since cookies don’t provide us with any information from which we can identify you, we suggest you allow us to place one on your computer.

If you visit our site by “clicking-through” from a site operated by one of our partners, and you have registered with that partner, then certain information about you that you have provided to that partner may be transmitted to us. You should review the privacy policy of the Web site from which you reached our site in order to determine what information was collected and how you agreed that our partner could use that information. Regardless of what information was transmitted to us, however, we don’t keep it unless you register with us.

## Registered Users

All users who choose to register themselves on our site www.sotc.in will be able to do online transactions with us. You will be able to purchase / book our services offered herein.

If you register with us, we will collect personal information from you in addition to the non-personal information described above. That personal information may include your name, email address, mailing address, telephone number, travel preferences, passport number, user name and password. The information we collect may vary, but we only collect the information that you manually enter into our forms. We may store all or some of that information in a cookie file on your hard drive, so that our system will recognize you each time you visit our site. In that way, we can save your preferences from visit to visit and present you with a customized Web site, without requiring you to log into our site every time you visit. To improve services and enhance personalization, we may periodically obtain information about you from other independent third-party sources and add it to your registration information. Additionally, authorized personnel may update your registration information to accurately reflect any new information included in communications received from you.

If you visit our site by “clicking-through” from a site operated by one of our partners, and you have registered with that partner, then certain information about you that you have provided to that partner may be transmitted to us. You should review the privacy policy of the Web site from which you reached our site in order to determine what information was collected and how you agreed that our partner could use that information. We may or may not retain that information; if we do, then we will only use it in accordance with our privacy policy, regardless of the policy of the partner site from which you came to us.

If you reach our site through one of our partners (whether or not you have registered with our partner), and you choose to register with us, we may be required to give our partner some or all of your registration information. We will only do so in accordance with this policy, but we cannot control how our partner uses the information. If you have questions about our partner’s privacy policy, you should review their policy before providing information to us. Of course, you can ensure that the personal information you provide to us is not shared with our partners (except in accordance with this policy), by visiting us directly instead of clicking-through from one of our partners.

## When you Purchase Products or Services for a third party

When you Purchase Products or Services for a third party using your Member ID and password, we will collect that third party’s name and contact information, and other information as required by the travel service provider(s), so that we can complete the booking.

## How we use the personal information we collect

We use the personal information we collect to help both of us! As we mentioned above, registering with us allows you to personalize our Web site so that it is most useful to you. It also allows you to log into our site automatically each time you visit, rather than manually typing your user name and password every time. By registering you can also track your history of transactions that you have done on our site which is available in the form of a Dossier. We may also use this information to periodically contact you with news or important information or to request your feedback on our site. In addition to these periodic updates, we may email you additional materials, but only if you specifically request them. These might include opt-in newsletters and other materials that you proactively request.

In addition to these communications, if you have provided an email address, we may use your personal information to send you notifications about special offers or to tell you about opportunities available from our partners. You may opt-out of any or all marketing communications in any commercial e-mail we send or at any time, as well as access and update your personal information, by visiting [www.sotc.in](http://www.sotc.in/)

## Disclosure of your personal information

KUONI does not sell or rent any personal information to any third party, other than our partners, as discussed in this policy. We may aggregate personal information from all of our users and provide that information in the aggregate to other parties, including advertisers, for marketing and promotional purposes. However, if we do so, that information will not be in a form that will allow any third party to identify you personally.

We may share some of your personally identifiable information with our subsidiaries and sister companies around the world that are committed to providing you with a comprehensive array of travel packages and services to meet your travel needs. Sharing this information allows us to better understand the ways in which our various product and service offerings can assist travelers. It also enables us to provide you with information about travel opportunities in which you might be interested. We do not place restrictions on the use of personal information by our subsidiaries, or affiliates but they will treat it at least as protectively as they treat information they obtain from their other users. They also will comply with applicable laws governing the transmission of promotional communications, and give you an opportunity in any such email that they send to choose not to receive such promotional e-mail messages in the future.

We also may share your personal information with third-parties specifically engaged by KUONI to provide services such as Airlines, Hotels, Ground Handlers, Insurance Companies, Product Companies and advertising agencies, in which case we will require those parties to agree to use any such personally-identifiable data solely for the purpose of providing the specified services to you. We may also use the information to provide to government agencies like RBI, Banks etc as per the laws of the country. As you might expect, KUONI must cooperate with legal authorities, and may in some circumstances be required to disclose personally identifiable information in response to requests from law enforcement authorities, or in response to a subpoena or other legal process. We don’t expect this to happen, but if it does, we will provide only the information required. In other words, we will not simply turn over our database in response to a specific legal requirement. We also may share your information in connection with a corporate transaction, such as a divestiture, merger, consolidation, or asset sale, and in the unlikely event of bankruptcy.

## How you can review and update your personal information

You can review and update the personal information you have provided through the registration process by visiting [www.sotc.in](http://www.sotc.in/)

## Steps we take to protect your personal information

KUONI has implemented security procedures to help protect the personal information stored in our systems. For example, we limit access to personal information about you to employees who we believe reasonably need to come into contact with that information. We also employ processes (such as password hashing, login auditing, and idle session termination) to protect against unauthorized access to your personal information.

## Minors

Minors (as defined under the laws of their jurisdiction or residence) are not eligible to register for, use, or Purchase the Products or Services available on our Site. We do not knowingly collect Personal Information from any Minor, and will not use this information if we discover that it has been provided by a Minor.

## Retention and storage

We will retain your Personal Information in our databases in accordance with our document management, retention and destruction policy and applicable laws. This period may extend beyond the end of your relationship with us, but it will be only as long as it is necessary for us to have sufficient information to respond to any issues that may arise later. For example, we may need or be required to retain information to allow you to obtain credit for trip your Purchased but had to cancel. We may also need the retain certain information to prevent fraudulent activity; to protect ourselves against liability, permit us to pursue available remedies or limit any damages that we may sustain; or if we believe in good faith that a law, regulation, rule or guideline requires it.

Your Personal Information will be stored in secured locations, and on servers controlled by KUONI, located either at our offices, or at the offices of our service providers

## Third Party Advertisers

Third parties advertise on our Site. We do not share any Personal Information about you with these advertisers unless you give us permission to do so, separate from any permission you provide during the Member registration process. These advertisers may seek to use cookies and pixel tags to track Session Data about the ads you have seen and types of things in which you appear interested. These advertisers may also use combined information about your visits to our Site and other sites in order to provide advertisements about related goods and services that may be of interest to you.

When you click on one of these advertisers’ links, you are leaving our Site and entering another site. We are not responsible for such third party’s sites. You should carefully review the privacy statements of any other site you visit, because those privacy statements will apply to your visit to that site, and may be very different from our policy.

## Opting-Out

As part of the registration process, we give you the ability to receive via e-mail or direct messaging information about our Products and Services, updates to our Site, customized advertisements and promotions that are targeted to your specific interest, such as flight specials, promotions, contests, sweepstakes and other travel opportunities available on our Site and/or sponsored by our travel service providers and advertisers. We send this information directly ourselves, or via third party service providers.

If you do not opt-out from receiving these communications about our Site, we will send them to you.

## Links

For your convenience, our Site provides links to other sites. When you click on one of these links, you are leaving our Site and entering another site. We are not responsible for such third party sites. You should carefully review the privacy statements of any other sites you visit, because those privacy statements will apply to your visit to such other sites.

## Changes to this Privacy Policy

We reserve the right to change this policy should we deem it advisable to do so. If we make material changes that will affect personal information we have already collected from you, we will make reasonable efforts to notify you of the changes and to give you the opportunity to amend or cancel your registration.

Copyright © SOTC Travel Services Pvt. Ltd. (Formerly Kuoni Travel (India) Pvt. Ltd.)  
Corporate Identification no: U63090MH1992PTC070074
